Kevin Parra

Software Engineer Colombia

Phone number: +57 3245945970 Portfolio: https://evinracher.github.io/
Email: kaparrahe@gmail.com
GitHub: https://github.com/evinracher

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/evinracher/

Summary

React Frontend Developer with over 3 years of experience, showcasing proficiency in React, JavaScript, TypeScript, CSS, HTML, and Jest for unit testing. Demonstrated versatility through work experience with both large-scale companies, such as Globant and Perficient (up to 21,000 employees), and small-scale companies like Talos (up to 100 employees). Familiar with a range of software tools and techniques, including Git, Next.js, Storybook, React Native, and more. Currently working as React.js Developer Consultant for Disney Media and Entertainment Distribution, within an international product team with about 30 developers with different roles.

Skills

- React.js
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- HTML

- CSS
- Jest
- React Testing Library (RTL)
- Next.js
- Git
- Reac Native

Experience

Frontend Developer (June 2022 - Present) Globant, Medellín

- Collaborated as a contractor with a development team of approximately 30 developers at Disney Media and Entertainment Distribution (DMED) to implement a content planning tool. The tool enables the listing and management of videos, movies, series, and other types of content to be displayed on various Disney platforms, including Disney+, Hulu, Star+, and ESPN+. This platform was built using React.js, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, Redux, RTL, Jest, Storybook, and GraphQL.
- Employed SCRUM and Kanban methodologies. Facilitated effective communication during pod meetings and took the lead in organizing formative sessions to promote clean code practices and principles among a team of up to 10 frontend developers.
- Conducted up to 2 code reviews per week, ensuring adherence to coding standards, maintaining code quality, and identifying areas for improvement.
- Implemented comprehensive unit tests to validate the functionality and behavior of the code, improving product quality and helped to have test coverage up to 85%.
- Participated in up to 30 candidate interviews, assessing their technical skills and evaluating their suitability for the team.

React Developer (September 2021 - June 2022) Perficient, Medellín

- Contributed as a React Engineer to a development team of up to 20 developers at All.health, a Silicon Valley-based company, in delivering an innovative healthcare platform.
- Managed and maintained a CMS product implemented with React.js, controlling content displayed to approximately 200 healthcare program patients and medical staff using a mobile health app.
- Automated tasks related to CMS content management. Handled up to 2000 pieces of health related content per week. Significantly reduced the time invested in this task from 3 months to 1 week, improving overall productivity and allowing more time for other critical activities.
- Developed a user-friendly survey application that facilitated up to 100 patients per month in applying for a Covid research health program, demonstrating problem solving skills.

Frontend Developer (August 2020 - September 2021) Talos Digital, Medellín

- Contributed to web projects for international clients as part of a startup team comprising up to 100 employees.
- Explored and applied various web development technologies such as React, HTML/CSS to enhance skills and knowledge.
- Developed a web forum for internal developers, facilitating discussions on training courses utilized, as part of a final university assessment. Received an outstanding grade for the project, demonstrating exceptional skills in web development and effective project management.

Languages

- Spanish (Native)
- English (Advanced)

Education

Engineer's degree, Computer Software Engineering (January 2017 - June 2021) Eafit University, Medellín

- Competed in the national edition of the ACM-ICPC programming marathon in 2017 and participated in both the national and regional editions in 2018.
- Participated in the Embedded Systems investigation group (SISE) as an advisor and coordinator, representing Eafit University in several regional research fairs.
- Engaged in the university's Taekwondo team.